<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>

<PP xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1"
    xmlns:sec="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1/section"
    xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" boilerplate="yes">  
  <!-- <inline-comment color='green'>Initial PSD-AI Template on 5/8.</inline-comment> -->
  <!-- <inline-comment color='blue' linebreak='yes'> Hello World QQQQ </inline-comment> -->
 
  <PPReference>
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>PP-Module for Analog Audio Output Devices</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>2.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2025-07-11</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>PSD, AO</Keywords>      
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2019-07-19</date>
      <subject>Initial draft</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <RevisionHistory>
    <version>2.0</version>
    <date>2025-07-11</date>
    <subject>Updates for CC:2022</subject>
  </RevisionHistory>

  <sec:Introduction>
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">
      The scope of this Protection Profile (PP)‐Module is to describe the security functionality of a specific type
      of Peripheral Sharing Device (PSD) product in terms of Common Criteria for Information Technology
      Security Evaluation, cc:2022, Release 1 [CC] and to define functional and assurance requirements for
      such products.<h:br/><h:br/>
      A Target of Evaluation (TOE) claiming conformance to this PP‐Module must also claim conformance to the
      Peripheral Sharing Device Protection Profile (PSD PP) as its Base‐PP. This is because the PSD PP is a generic
      Protection Profile aimed at defining baseline requirements and Evaluation Activities for a wide variety of
      PSD products, but more specific requirements and Evaluation Activities apply depending on the types of
      physical and logical interfaces a PSD includes. Therefore, this PP‐Module defines additional Security
      Functional Requirements (SFRs) for security functionality unique to a PSD that supports peripheral audio
      output devices.      
    </section>
    
    <tech-terms>
      <term full="Analog Audio">
        Data stream that uses voltage to describe a sound wave.
      </term>
      <term full="Analog Audio Output Computer Interface, or Computer Interface">
        The connector on a PSD through which analog audio data enters the PSD from a connected
        computer.
      </term>
      <term full="Analog Audio Output Peripheral Interface, or Peripheral Interface">
        The connector on a PSD through which analog audio data exits the PSD bound for a
        peripheral device.
      </term>      
      <term full="Attenuation">
        A reduction in signal strength commonly occurring while transmitting analog or
        digital signals over long distances.
      </term>
      <term full="Audio codec">
        PC subsystem capable of encoding and decoding a digital data stream of audio.
      </term>
      <term full="Audio Output Peripheral Device">
        Speakers, handset, and earphones.
      </term>      
      <term abbr="dB" full="Decibel"/>
      <term abbr="dBv" full="Decibel Volt">
        A measurement of voltage ratio to 1 volt.
      </term>
      <term full="Digital Audio">
        Data stream that uses digital values to describe a sound wave in sampled intervals.
      </term>
      <term full="Extended Audio Frequency Range">
        The range from 1Hz to 60 kHz.
      </term>
      <term full="Headphones">
        Computer audio peripheral device with one or more small speakers.
      </term>
      <term abbr="KHz" full="Kilohertz"/>
      <term abbr="mV" full="Millivolt"/>
      <term abbr='PSD' full="Peripheral Sharing Device"/>
      <term abbr='S/PDIF' full="Sony/Philips Digital Interface Format"/>
      <term full="USB Audio codec">
        Computer audio peripheral device with USB digital input/output, one or more
        analog audio outputs and one or more analog audio inputs.
      </term>
    </tech-terms>    
    
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">
      A compliant Target of Evaluation (TOE) for this PP‐Module is any PSD that supports connectivity between
      one or more computers and one or more analog audio output peripheral devices. All of the requirements
      and restrictions that are defined in the PSD PP apply to a conformant TOE. A conformant TOE satisfies all
      of the specific data protection/isolation capabilities that are required by the PSD PP.<h:br/><h:br/>
      A conformant TOE embodies one or more of the use cases defined in the PSD PP. It may also provide PSD
      functionality for additional types of computer interfaces (e.g., display, keyboard/mouse, user
      authentication device). In such a case, the TOE must claim conformance to all applicable PP‐Modules to
      the PSD PP.<h:br/><h:br/>
      In general, computer audio may be routed in various ways:<h:ul>
        <h:li>Analog audio signals</h:li>
        <h:li>Digital audio embedded in the video stream or independent digital audio (e.g., Sony/Philips Digital
          Interface Format, or S/PDIF)</h:li>
        <h:li>USB audio peripheral devices</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      Analog audio output requires special attention during TOE design as it may introduce analog leakage
      concerns. There is an additional concern an attacker may be able to use an audio output device as a lowgain
      microphone for eavesdropping on the surrounding area or bridging an air‐gap to nearby computers.
      Analog audio output presents few security problems with respect to switching, since the person listening
      to the audio must be authorized to hear the output of all the connected computers. And in some
      operational environments, it is required that the user be able to hear more than one channel at a time.<h:br/><h:br/>
      Digital audio embedded in a video stream or passed through separate lines is not a security concern for
      this PP‐Module since it does not introduce analog signal leakage vulnerabilities. The capability for digital
      video is addressed in the PP‐Module for Video/Display Devices.<h:br/><h:br/>
      USB audio devices (i.e., codecs) are not authorized for use with the TOE. USB audio codecs have
      configuration memory that may be exploited to enable unauthorized data flows.
    </section>      
      <section title="TOE Boundary" id="TOEboundary">
        The TOE boundary is the same as for a Peripheral Sharing Device in general. Refer to the PSD PP for an
        outline of the TOE boundary. Note that a TOE that claims conformance to this PP‐Module must specifically
        include support for analog audio output peripherals. A TOE that claims conformance to this PP‐Module is
        not prevented from claiming conformance to other PSD PP‐Modules. All relevant PP‐Modules must be
        claimed by the TOE based on the specific types of peripheral device functionality provided.
      </section>      
    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
      No additional use cases are defined for this PP‐Module. The TOE is expected to embody one or more use
      cases as defined by the PSD PP. The functionality defined by this PP‐Module is implementationindependent
      (i.e., not tied to any specific use cases) and is related entirely to the specific security
      requirements related to security of the physical and logical interfaces for analog audio output devices.
    </section>    
  </sec:Introduction>

  <section title="Conformance Claims" id="sec-cclaims" boilerplate="no">
    <CClaimsInfo
      cc-version="cc-2022r1"
      cc-approach="direct-rationale"
      display="yes">
      <cc-st-conf>exact</cc-st-conf>
      <cc-pt2-conf>extended</cc-pt2-conf>           
      <cc-pt3-conf>conformant</cc-pt3-conf> 
      <cc-pp-conf/>
      <cc-pp-config-with>
        <PP-cc-ref>Protection Profile for Peripheral Sharing Device, Version 5.0</PP-cc-ref>
        <Mod-cc-ref>PP-Module for Keyboard/Mouse Devices, Version 1.0</Mod-cc-ref>
        <Mod-cc-ref>PP-Module for User Authentication Devices, Version 1.0</Mod-cc-ref>
        <Mod-cc-ref>PP-MOdule for Video/Display Devices, Version 1.0</Mod-cc-ref>
      </cc-pp-config-with>        
      <cc-pkg-claim/>
    </CClaimsInfo>
  </section>
  
  <sec:spd title="Security Problem Description">    
    <sec:Threats>
      This PP‐Module describes the security problem in terms of the threats the TOE is expected to address,
      assumptions about its operational environment, and any organizational security policies (OSPs) that the
      TOE is expected to enforce.<h:br/><h:br/>
      Note that as a PP‐Module of the PSD PP, all threats, assumptions, and Organizational Security Policies (OSP)
      defined in the base PP will also apply to the TOE unless otherwise specified.
      <threat name="T.AUDIO_REVERSED">
        <description>A malicious agent could repurpose an authorized audio output peripheral device by converting it to a
          low‐gain microphone to eavesdrop on the surrounding audio or transfer data across an air‐gap
          through audio signaling.</description>
        <consistency-rationale>The PSD PP does not identify any threats specific to analog audio output
          peripheral devices. This threat is specific to analog audio output devices and
          therefore is an additional threat to this module supplementing those in PSD
          PP.</consistency-rationale>        
        <addressed-by>FDP_APC_EXT.1 (Modified)</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_AFL_EXT.1</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
      </threat>
            
      <threat name="T.DATA_LEAK">
        <from base="bpp-psd"/>
        <addressed-by>FDP_APC_EXT.1 (Modified)</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_AFL_EXT.1</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
      </threat>
      
      <threat name="T.MICROPHONE_USE">        
        <addressed-by>FDP_APC_EXT.1 (Modified)</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_AFL_EXT.1</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
      </threat>

      <threat name="T.SIGNAL_LEAK">
        <from base="bpp-psd"/>
        <addressed-by>FDP_APC_EXT.1 (Modified)</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_AFL_EXT.1</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
        <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by><rationale></rationale>
      </threat>

    </sec:Threats>
    
    <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
      This PP‐Module defines the following additional assumption beyond those defined in the PSD PP
      <assumptions name="A.NO_MICROPHONES">
        Users are trained not to connect a microphone to the TOE audio output interface.<h:br/><h:br/>
        Note that this assumption is necessary despite the fact that the TSF enforces unidirectional data flow (see
        O.UNIDIRECTIONAL_AUDIO_OUT) below because the signals are analog and not digital. Because of this, it
        is not possible to make the pathway truly unidirectional; instead, the TSF can only diminish the strength
        of audio signals such that usable data cannot be transmitted. The assumption that microphones are
        prohibited is used to enforce a defense‐in‐depth strategy for mitigating the threat of audio reversal.
      </assumptions>
    </section>
    
    <sec:Organizational_Security_Polcies>
      <OSPs/>
    </sec:Organizational_Security_Polcies>
  </sec:spd>

  <sec:Security_Objectives>
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
      A TOE conforming to this PP‐Module must address the O.COMPUTER_INTERFACE_ISOLATION,
      O.COMPUTER_INTERFACE_ISOLATION_UNPOWERED, O.USER_DATA_ISOLATION,
      O.PERIPHERAL_PORTS_ISOLATION, and O.REJECT_UNAUTHORIZED_PERIPHERAL objectives from the PSD
      PP specifically for audio output peripherals. In addition to the SFRs mapped in the PSD PP, the following
      SFRs defined in this PP‐Module or modified from their PSD PP definition contribute to supporting these
      objectives for audio output devices:<h:ul>
        <h:li>FDP_APC_EXT.1 (modified from PSD PP definition), FDP_PDC_EXT.1 (modified from PSD PP
      definition), FDP_PDC_EXT.2/AO, FDP_PUD_EXT.1</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      The following security objectives are defined by this PP‐Module for a TOE that claims conformance to this
      PP‐Module.      
    </section>    
    
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment" id="SecurityObjectivesTOEorEnvironment">
      <SOEs>
        <SOE name="OE.NO_MICROPHONES">
          <description>The operational environment is expected to ensure that microphones are not plugged into the TOE
            audio output interfaces.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>The assumption is upheld by the objective
            since the users in the environment are trained
            not to connect a microphone to the TOE audio
            output interface.</consistency-rationale>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
      </section>    
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="SOR"/>
  </sec:Security_Objectives>

  <sec:Security_Requirements>
    
    <base-pp id="bpp-psd" name="Peripheral Sharing Device" product="Device" short="PSD" version="5.0">
      <git>
        <url><comment>Need to add URL once created</comment></url>
        <branch>release-5.0</branch>
      </git>
      <url><comment>Need to add URL once created</comment></url>
      
      <sec-func-req-dir>
        When a TOE claims compliance to this PP‐Module, it is necessary to make claims in the PSD PP
        requirements that are consistent with the functionality provided by the PP‐Module. The following sections
        describe any PSD PP claims that must be made when the TOE boundary includes the functionality
        described by this PP‐Module. Note that for some requirements, only certain individual elements within
        the SFR have been modified for this PP‐Module. Any SFR elements that were omitted from the selections
        below are to be included in a conformant ST unmodified from their definition in the PSD PP.
      </sec-func-req-dir>
      
      <modified-sfrs>
        <section title="User Data Protection (FDP)">
          <f-component cc-id="fdp_apc_ext.1" name="Active PSD Connections">
            <consistency-reationale>
              This refined SFR accounts for analog and electrical signals which are not listed
              in the PSD PP.
            </consistency-reationale>
            <f-element id="fdp-apc-ext.1e1">
            <title> The TSF shall route user data only to <h:s>or from</h:s> the interfaces selected by the
              user. 
            </title>
            </f-element>
            <f-element id="fdp-apc-ext.1e2">
              <title>The TSF shall ensure that no data <h:b>or electrical signals</h:b>flow between connected computers whether the
                TOE is powered on or powered off.
              </title>
              <note role="application">
                This SFR is refined from the PSD PP for this PP‐Module to include further
                restrictions for electrical signals. It is very unlikely that this element can be
                satisfied unless all unselected computer interfaces are shorted to ground by the
                TSF.<h:br/><h:br/>
                If computer interface supports right and left audio, or audio and microphone bias,
                then all those supported signals should comply with the above SFRs.
              </note>
              <aactivity>
                Because of the specific nature of the audio input data that transits the TOE, there
                are additional EAs for this SFR.
                <Isolation>
                  The evaluator shall examine the Isolation Documentation to determine that it describes the logic under
                  which the TSF permits audio flows from a connected audio input peripheral to a connected computer
                  interface.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  The evaluator shall examine the Isolation Documentation to determine that it describes how the TOE
                  enforces audio input data flow isolation from other TOE functions, such that it is not possible for two
                  computers connected to the TOE to use the TOE to communicate with one another. The description shall
                  ensure the signal attenuation in the extended audio frequency range between any TOE audio input
                  interface and any other computer audio input interface is at least 45 dB measured with a 2V input pure
                  sine wave at the extended audio frequency range, including negative swing signal.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  The evaluator shall examine the Isolation Documentation to determine that it describes how the TOE
                  prevents the audio input signal from traversing the TOE while the TOE is powered off.
                </Isolation>
                <TSS>
                  There are no TSS EAs for this component beyond what the PSD PP requires.
                </TSS>
                <Guidance>
                  If the ability of the TOE to route analog audio input signals is configurable, the evaluator shall verify that
                  the operational guidance describes how to configure the TSF to behave in the manner specified by the
                  SFR. This includes the possibility of both administratively configured TOE settings and any
                  peripherals/connectors that are included with the TOE that cause data flows to behave differently if
                  peripherals are connected through them.
                </Guidance>
                <Test>
                  The evaluator shall then perform the following tests:
                  <testlist>
                    <test>
                      <h:b>AI: Positive and Negative Analog Audio Input Switching Functionality and Leakages</h:b><h:br/><h:br/>
                      AI verifies that the switching functionality works as expected and checks for leakage to non-selected
                      computers when the audio source is connected to the peripheral interface. In the following steps, the
                      evaluator shall confirm that an analog audio signal traversing the TOE from an analog audio source to
                      one user‐selected connected computer does not leak to the non‐selected computers’ analog audio interfaces.<h:br/><h:br/>
                      <h:b>Part 1a: Peripheral to Selected Computer Flow</h:b><h:ol>
                        <h:li>Connect the microphone to the TOE Analog Audio Input peripheral interface.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Connect a computer to each TOE Analog Audio Input computer interface, and configure the
                            computers’ ports for microphone input.</h:li>
                        <h:li>For each connected computer, select its interface and perform steps 4‐5.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Speak into the microphone. Verify that the connected computer picks up the audio by recording
                            the audio or viewing the microphone audio level.</h:li>
                        <h:li>[Conditional: This step is performed if “the TOE supports only one connected computer” is
                            selected for FDP_SWI_EXT.1.1] Speak into the microphone. Verify that each non‐selected
                            connected computer does not pick up the audio by recording the audio or viewing the microphone
                            audio level.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Power down the TOE.</h:li>
                        <h:li>For each connected computer, select its interface and perform step 8.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Speak into the microphone. Verify that the connected computer does not pick up the audio by
                            recording the audio or viewing the microphone audio level.</h:li>
                      </h:ol>
                      <h:b>Part 1b: Peripheral to Non-Selected Computer Flow and Frequency Verification</h:b><h:ol>
                        <h:li>Power on the TOE and connect a tone generator to the TOE audio input peripheral interface and
                            set it to maximum line output level.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Connect amplified speakers to each of the TOE computer interfaces and set the volume to 0%.</h:li>
                        <h:li>For each connected computer, select its interface and perform steps 4‐6.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Use the tone generator to generate a sine wave audio tone for each of the following frequencies:
                            100 Hz, 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 1 kHz, 2 kHz, 4 kHz, 8 kHz, 10 kHz, 12 kHz, 15 kHz, 20 kHz, 30 kHz, 40 kHz,
                            50 kHz, and 60 kHz. Gradually turn up the volume on each set of speakers until the tone can be
                            heard or the volume reaches 100%. Reset the volume to 0% after testing each channel. Note:
                            Depending on shielding the speakers might pick up air‐conditioning (50 or 60 Hz). This is not
                            considered a failure.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Verify that the injected test tone is heard only on the speakers connected to the selected
                            computer.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Replace the speakers attached to a computer interface with an oscilloscope and set to measure
                            the peak‐to‐peak voltage.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Attach computers to the other TOE computer interfaces.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Select a computer interface other than the one to which the oscilloscope is connected.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Replace the tone generator with an external audio signal generator and perform step 10 with the
                            signal generator set to the following settings:<h:ul>
                              <h:li>Pure sine wave around the average voltage of half output (positive signal only), with the
                                output signal set to 2.00 V peak‐to‐peak, calibrating the signal with the oscilloscope as needed</h:li>
                              <h:li>Signal average to 0v (negative swing)</h:li>
                            </h:ul></h:li>
                        <h:li>Set the signal generator to generate 100 Hz, 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 1 kHz, 2 kHz, 4 kHz, 8 kHz, 10 kHz, 12
                          kHz, 15 kHz, 20 kHz, 30 kHz, 40 kHz, 50 kHz, and 60 kHz and use the oscilloscope to detect the
                          leaked signal. Verify the detected signal is 11.2 mV (or well below noise level). This level of signal
                          ensures signal attenuation of 45 dB in the extended audio frequency range.</h:li><h:br/><h:br/>
                        [Conditional: The below steps are performed if switching through express user action is selected for
                        FDP_SWI_EXT.1.1]<h:br/><h:br/>
                        <h:li>Repeat steps 8‐10 with each of the other computer interfaces selected.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Repeat steps 8‐11 with the oscilloscope attached to a different computer interface until all
                            computer interfaces have been tested.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Power down the TOE, repeat steps 8‐12, verifying that the results are the same as previously
                            tested in those steps.</h:li>
                      </h:ol>
                    </test>
                    <test>
                      <h:b>AI: Computer Isolation</h:b><h:br/><h:br/>
                      [Conditional: This test is performed if “switching can be initiated only through express user action” is
                      selected for FDP_SWI_EXT.1.1]<h:br/><h:br/>
                      AI verifies that audio data cannot flow between computer interfaces whether or not any computer
                      interfaces are selected. It intends to test every combination of audio source, selected computer interface,
                      and oscilloscope location for all computer interfaces.<h:br/><h:br/>
                      Note: When the signal inserted on one TOE computer interface audio input is 2.00 V peak‐to‐peak sine
                      wave, the maximum allowed output signal voltage measured at another TOE computer interface is
                      therefore 11.2mV (or well below noise level). The extended audio frequency range is 1Hz to 60 kHz.
                      Negative swing is measured when the generated audio signal average voltage is 0V.<h:br/><h:br/>
                      In the following steps the evaluator shall verify that the TOE does not allow significant leakage between
                      Audio In computer interfaces:<h:ol>
                        <h:li>Disconnect the tone generator from the Analog Audio Input peripheral interface. Leave the
                        receptacle empty.</h:li>
                        <h:li>For each computer interface, perform steps 3‐6.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Connect the tone generator to the selected first computer interface and ensure it is not selected.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Connect amplified speakers to each remaining computer interface. Set the volume of the speakers
                        to 0%.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Use the tone generator to generate a sine wave audio tone for each of the following frequencies:
                        100 Hz, 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 1 kHz, 2 kHz, 4 kHz, 8 kHz, 10 kHz, 12 kHz, 15 kHz, 20 kHz, 30 kHz, 40 kHz,
                        50 kHz, and 60 kHz. Gradually turn up the volume on each set of speakers until the tone can be
                        heard or the volume reaches 100%. Reset the volume to 0% after testing each channel. Note:
                        Depending on shielding the speakers might pick up AC (50 or 60 Hz). This is not considered a
                        failure.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Verify that a tone is not heard.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Attach an external audio signal generator to a computer interface and set to pure sine wave
                        around the average voltage of half output (positive signal only). Set the output signal to 2.00V
                        peak‐to‐peak. (The oscilloscope may be used to calibrate the signal.)</h:li>
                        <h:li>Attach the oscilloscope to the next computer interface.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Select the interface with the signal generator.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Set the signal generator to generate 100 Hz, 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 1 kHz, 2 kHz, 4 kHz, 8 kHz, 10 kHz, 12
                        kHz, 15 kHz, 20 kHz, 30 kHz, 40 kHz, 50 kHz, and 60 kHz and use the oscilloscope to detect the
                        leaked signal. Verify the detected signal is 11.2mV (or well below noise level). This level of signal
                        ensures signal attenuation of 45 dB in the extended audio frequency range.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Repeat step 10 with the audio generator set to signal average to 0V (negative swing). Verify the
                        detected signal is 11.2mV (or well below noise level). This level of signal ensures signal attenuation
                        of 45 dB in the extended audio frequency range.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Disconnect the power to the TOE and repeat Steps 10‐11 without the assignment of specific
                        computers. Verify the attenuation results are the same as for the powered on TOE.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Power up the TOE again. Repeat steps 10‐12 for each selected computer interface. (This tests
                        both for leakage between selected and non‐selected computer interfaces, and between pairs of
                        non‐selected computer interfaces).</h:li>
                        <h:li>Repeat steps 10‐13 with the oscilloscope connected to each computer interface not connected
                        to the signal generator.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Repeat steps 10-14 with the signal generator connected to each of the
                          other computer interfaces.</h:li></h:ol>
                    </test>
                    <test>
                      <h:b>Behavior of TOE in Failure State and Powered-Off Mode</h:b><h:br/><h:br/>
                      Test 3 verifies that analog audio data cannot traverse the TOE when the TOE is
                      in a failure state or powered-off.<h:br/><h:br/>
                      The evaluator shall confirm that an analog audio signal does not traverse the
                      TOE while the TOE is in a failure state:<h:ol>
                        <h:li>Power off the TOE.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Connect a tone generator to the TOE peripheral interface.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Connect amplified speakers to each of the TOE Audio In computer interfaces.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Perform steps 5 and 6 while the TOE is powered off and while the TOE is powered on and entered
                        into a failure state.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Use the tone generator to generate a sine wave audio tone for each of the following frequencies:
                        100 Hz, 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 1 kHz, 2 kHz, 4 kHz, 8 kHz, 10 kHz, 12 kHz, 15 kHz, 20 kHz, 30 kHz, 40 kHz,
                        50 kHz, and 60 kHz. Gradually turn up the volume on each set of speakers until the tone can be
                        heard or the volume reaches 100%. Reset the volume to 0% after testing each channel. Note:
                        Depending on shielding the speakers might pick up AC (50 or 60 Hz). This is not considered a
                        failure.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Verify that a tone is not heard.</h:li></h:ol>
                    </test>
                  </testlist>
                </Test>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
        </section>
        
        <section title="Peripheral Device Connection" id="modsfr-psd-fdp-pdc-ext-1">
          There is no modification to this SFR in this PP‐Module. However, there are additions to the supported
          peripheral device connections (see Appendix E) that are associated with this SFR.
          <con-toe>
            This SFR is not modified, but it references Appendix E which is modified in this
            PP‐Module to apply to audio input devices which are not listed in the PSD PP.
          </con-toe>
          <aactivity>
            <Isolation/>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall verify that the TSS describes the peripherals that are supported by the TOE to ensure
              that it does not support any peripherals other than audio input devices.
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall verify that the operational user guidance describes devices authorized for use with the
              TOE in accordance with the Peripheral Device Connection Policy.
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              <testlist>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall verify that the TOE ports properly reject unauthorized devices and devices
                  with unauthorized protocols as per the Peripheral Device Connection Policy.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  For this test, verify device rejection through TOE user indication in accordance with the operational user
                  guidance, an immediate cessation of traffic following device detection or enumeration, or incompatibility
                  of the device interface with the peripheral interface.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  Repeat this test for each of the following devices: digital microphone, keyboard, mouse, any device using
                  digital video protocol, any device using USB protocol.<h:ol>
                    <h:li>Ensure the TOE is powered off.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Attempt to connect an unauthorized device to the TOE peripheral interface.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Power on the TOE. Verify the device is rejected.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Ensure the unauthorized device is disconnected, then attempt to connect it to the TOE peripheral
                  interface again.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Verify the device is rejected.</h:li>
                  </h:ol>
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall verify that the TOE ports do not reject authorized devices and devices with
                  authorized protocols as per the Peripheral Device Connection Policy.<h:ol>
                    <h:li>Ensure the TOE is powered off.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Connect the authorized device to the TOE peripheral interface.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Power on the TOE. Verify the TOE user indication described in the operational user guidance is not
                  present.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Speak into the microphone. Verify that the connected computer picks up the audio by recording
                  the audio or viewing the microphone audio level.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Disconnect the microphone, then reconnect it to the TOE peripheral interface.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Verify the TOE user indication described in the operational user guidance is not present.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Speak into the microphone. Verify that the connected computer picks up the audio by recording
                  the audio or viewing the microphone audio level.</h:li>
                  </h:ol>                   
                </test>
              </testlist>
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </section>
      </modified-sfrs>
      
      <additional-sfrs/>
      
      <con-toe>
        The PSD PP defines the boundaries of a PSD—a device that provides a mechanism for securely connecting
        a set of peripherals to one or more attached computers. This PP‐Module builds on this by defining
        functional capabilities that are specific to audio input devices. One of the functions of the device must be
        the ability for it to act as an audio input device. The requirements of this PP do not prevent a conformant
        TOE from implementing mandatory requirements of the PSD PP.
      </con-toe>
      <con-sec-prob>
        This PP‐Module does not define any additional threats beyond those defined in the PSD PP. Therefore,
        there is no inconsistency between the threats defined in the PSD PP and this PP‐Module.
      </con-sec-prob>
      <con-obj>
        The PSD PP does not define any TOE objectives; therefore, there is no inconsistency between it and this
        PP‐Module. The requirements defined in this PP‐Module are intended to satisfy objectives already defined
        in the PSD PP in a more specific manner.
      </con-obj>
      <con-op-en>
        This PP-Module does not define any objectives for the TOE's operational environment.
      </con-op-en>
    </base-pp>
    
    <man-sfrs>
      <section title="User Data Protection (FDP)" id="FDP">
        <ext-comp-def fam-id="FDP_PDC_EXT" title="Authorized Devices (Analog Audio Input)">
          <fam-behavior>This family is defined in the PSD PP. This PP‐Module augments the extended family by adding one
            additional component, FDP_PDC_EXT.2. This new component and its impact on the extended family’s
            component leveling are shown below; reference the PSD PP for all other definitions for this family.</fam-behavior>
        </ext-comp-def>
        
        <ext-comp-def fam-id="FDP_UDF_EXT" title="Unidirectional Data Flow">
          <fam-behavior>Components in this family define unidirectional transmission of user data.</fam-behavior>
        </ext-comp-def>
        
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_pdc_ext.2" name="Authorized Devices (Analog Audio Input)" iteration="AI" id="fdp-pdc-ext-2-ai">
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR defines the devices that are authorized by this PP‐Module. This is
            dependent on the other PP‐Modules that are claimed in the TOE’s ST. The
            Base‐PP is written specifically not to discuss the supported device types,
            instead leaving it to the various PP‐Modules to define what they support.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev>defines the types of physical devices that the TSF will permit to
            connect to it.</comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified</management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
          <dependencies>FDP_PDC_EXT.1 Peripheral Device Connection</dependencies>
          
          <f-element id="fdp-pdc-ext-2e1-ai">
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices as defined in [<h:i>Appendix
                E</h:i>] and [<h:i>no other devices</h:i>] on power-up and upon connection of a peripheral device
              to a powered‐on TOE.
            </title>
            
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices as defined in
                <assignable>devices specified in the PP or PP‐Module in which this SFR is defined</assignable>
                and <assignable>devices specified in another PP or PP‐Module that shares a PPConfiguration
                with the PP or PP‐Module in which this SFR is defined</assignable> upon TOE
                power up and upon connection of a peripheral device to a powered‐on TOE.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fdp-pdc-ext-2e2-ai">
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices presenting authorized
              interface protocols as defined in [<h:i>Appendix E</h:i>] and [<h:i>no other devices</h:i>] upon TOE
              power up and upon connection of a peripheral device to a powered‐on TOE.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices presenting authorized
                interface protocols as defined in <assignable>devices specified in the PP or PPModule
                in which this SFR is defined</assignable> and <assignable>devices specified in another
                PP or PP‐Module that shares a PP‐Configuration with the PP or PP‐Module in
                which this SFR is defined</assignable> upon TOE power up and upon connection of a
                peripheral device to a powered‐on TOE.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            <note role="application">
              A TOE that claims conformance to this PP‐Module is not permitted to conform to
              any other PP‐Modules that extend the PSD PP. Therefore, no other devices or
              protocols will be supported beyond those that are defined in this PP‐Module.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <Isolation/>
              <TSS>
                TSS evaluation activities for this SFR are performed under FDP_PDC_EXT.1 above.
              </TSS>
              <Guidance>
                Guidance evaluation activities for this SFR are performed under FDP_PDC_EXT.1 above.
              </Guidance>
              <Tests>
                Testing of this component is performed through evaluation of FDP_PDC_EXT.1 Test 2 as specified in
                section 2.2.1.2 above.
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_udf_ext.1" name="Unidirectional Data flow (Analog Audio Input)" iteration="AI" id="fdp-udf-ext-2-ai">
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to unidirectional audio communications which are not listed
            in the PSD PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev>requires the TSF to provide unidirectional (one‐way)
            communications between a given pair of interface types.</comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
          <dependencies>FDP_APC_EXT.1 Active PSD Connections</dependencies>  
          
          <f-element id="fdp-udf-ext.1e1-ai">
            <title>
              The TSF shall ensure that [<h:i>analog audio input data</h:i>] transits the TOE
              unidirectionally from the [<h:i>TOE analog audio input peripheral interface</h:i>] to the
              [<h:i>TOE analog audio input computer interface</h:i>].
            </title>
            
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall ensure <assignable>type of data</assignable> data transits the TOE
                unidirectionally from the <assignable>origin point of data] interface to the
                [assignment: destination point of data</assignable> interface.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            
            <note role="application">
              This SFR applies to all types of analog audio input data (e.g., if the computer
              interface supports left and right audio, or audio and microphone bias).<h:br/><h:br/>
              For audio signals, the TOE analog audio input peripheral interface is considered
              to be unidirectional if it receives no signal greater than 45 decibels (dB) of
              attenuation at the extended audio frequency range.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <Isolation/>
              <TSS>
                The evaluator shall examine the TSS or the Isolation Document to determine that it describes how the
                TOE enforces audio input data flow isolation from other TOE functions, such that the audio input
                peripheral interface is unidirectional and no data can be transmitted from a connected computer back to
                a connected peripheral. The description shall ensure the signal attenuation in the extended audio
                frequency range between any TOE audio input interface and any other computer audio input interface is
                at least 45 dB measured with a 2V input pure sine wave at the extended audio frequency range, including
                negative swing signal.
              </TSS>
              <Guidance/>
              <Tests>
                The evaluator shall perform the following test.<h:ol>
                  <h:li>Configure the TOE in accordance with the operational guidance. Power on the TOE.</h:li>
                  <h:li>Connect an oscilloscope to the TOE Peripheral Interface. Perform step 3‐4 for each TOE Audio In
                Computer Interface.</h:li>
                  <h:li>Connect an external audio signal generator to the TOE Audio In computer interface and perform
                step 4 with the signal generator set to the following settings.<h:ul>
                  <h:li>Pure sine wave around the average voltage of half output (positive signal only), with the
                      output signal set to 2.00 V peak‐to‐peak, calibrating the signal with the oscilloscope as
                      needed.</h:li>
                  <h:li>Signal average to 0v (negative swing)</h:li>
                </h:ul>
                  </h:li>
                  <h:li>Set the signal generator to generate 100 Hz, 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 1 kHz, 2 kHz, 4 kHz, 8 kHz, 10 kHz, 12
                kHz, 15 kHz, 20 kHz, 30 kHz, 40 kHz, 50 kHz, and 60 kHz and use the oscilloscope to detect the
                leaked signal. Verify the detected signal is 11.2 mV (or well below noise level). This level of signal
                ensures signal attenuation of 45 dB in the extended audio frequency range</h:li>
                </h:ol>                
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>  
        </f-component>        
      </section>      
    </man-sfrs>
    <opt-sfrs/>
    <sel-sfrs/>
    <obj-sfrs/>
    <impl-dep-sfrs/>
  </sec:Security_Requirements>

  <appendix title="Isolation Documentation and Assessment" id="iso-doc-assess">
    The TOE does not require any additional supplementary information to describe its isolation concepts
    beyond the requirements outlined in the ‘Isolation Documentation and Assessment’ sections in Appendix
    D of the PSD PP. As with other PSD PP requirements, the only additional requirement is that the isolation
    documentation also applies to the specific isolation and data flow SFRs in this PP‐module in addition to
    the functionality required by the PSD PP.
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="Peripheral Device Connections">
    <section title="General">
      This appendix expands the PSD PP Peripheral Device Connections appendix, and offers additional direction
      on peripheral devices and interface protocols with TOEs claiming compliance with this PP‐Module. This
      appendix is in conjunction with the PSD PP’s appendix and does not replace it.
    </section>
    
    <section title="Unauthorized Peripheral Devices">
      The following are unauthorized device classes:<h:ul>
        <h:li>Digital microphone</h:li>
        <h:li>Keyboard</h:li>
        <h:li>Mouse</h:li>
        <h:li>Any device not specifically authorized</h:li>
      </h:ul>     
    </section>
    
    <section title="Unauthorized Interface Protocols">
      The following are unauthorized interface protocols:<h:ul>
        <h:li>Digital audio</h:li>
        <h:li>Digital video</h:li>
        <h:li>USB</h:li>
        <h:li>Any other protocol not specifically authorized</h:li>
      </h:ul>
    </section>
    <section title="Authorized Peripheral Devices">
      The following are authorized devices and functions:<h:ul>
        <h:li>Analog microphone</h:li>
      </h:ul>
    </section>
    <section title="Authorized Interface Protocols">
      The following are authorized interface protocols:<h:ul>
        <h:li>Analog audio input</h:li>
      </h:ul>
    </section>
  </appendix> 
  
  <bibliography>    
    <entry id="bibCESG">
      <tag>CESG</tag>
      <description>CESG - <h:a
      href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/end-user-devices-security-guidance"> End
      User Devices Security and Configuration Guidance</h:a></description>
    </entry>
    <entry id="bibCSA">
      <tag>CSA</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/SMA/ispab/documents/csa_87.txt">Computer Security Act
      of 1987</h:a>, H.R. 145, June 11, 1987. </description>
    </entry>
    <entry id="bibOMB">
      <tag>OMB</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/memoranda/fy2006/m06-19.pdf"
             >Reporting Incidents Involving Personally Identifiable Information and Incorporating the
        Cost for Security in Agency Information Technology Investments</h:a>, OMB M-06-19, July
      12, 2006. </description>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <tag>PP_PSD_V5.0 or PSD PP</tag>
      <h:a href=""><comment>Need to add URL once published.</comment>Protection Profile for Peripheral Sharing Device, Version 5.0, 2025-07-11</h:a>
    </entry>
  </bibliography>

    </PP>