<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\transforms\module2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="../transforms/schemas/CCModule.rng" type="application/xml"?>
<Module name="Analog Audio Output Devices" boilerplate="yes" target-product="Audio Output Device" target-products="Audio Output Devices" xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:sec="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1/section" short="AI">
  <PPReference>
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPVersion>2.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2025-07-11</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>PSD, AO</Keywords>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2019-07-19</date>
      <subject>Initial draft</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <pp-preferences/>
  <sec:Introduction>
    <section id="ppoverview" title="Overview">
      The scope of this Protection Profile (PP)‐Module is to describe the security functionality of a specific type
      of Peripheral Sharing Device (PSD) product in terms of Common Criteria for Information Technology
      Security Evaluation, cc:2022, Release 1 [CC] and to define functional and assurance requirements for
      such products.
      <h:br/>
      <h:br/>
      A Target of Evaluation (TOE) claiming conformance to this PP‐Module must also claim conformance to the
      Protection Profile for Peripheral Sharing Devices (PSD PP) as its Base‐PP. This is because the PSD PP is a generic
      Protection Profile aimed at defining baseline requirements and Evaluation Activities for a wide variety of
      PSD products, but more specific requirements and Evaluation Activities apply depending on the types of
      physical and logical interfaces a PSD includes. Therefore, this PP‐Module defines additional Security
      Functional Requirements (SFRs) for security functionality unique to a PSD that supports peripheral audio
      output devices.
      <h:br/>
      <h:br/>
      This PP-Module is intended for use with the following Base-PPs:
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Peripheral Sharing Devices Protection Profile, Version 5.0</h:li>
      </h:ul>
    </section>
    <tech-terms>
      <term full="Analog Audio">Data stream that uses voltage to describe a sound wave.</term>
      <term full="Analog Audio Output Computer Interface, or Computer Interface">The connector on a PSD through which analog audio data enters the PSD from a connected
        computer.</term>
      <term full="Analog Audio Output Peripheral Interface, or Peripheral Interface">The connector on a PSD through which analog audio data exits the PSD bound for a
        peripheral device.</term>
      <term full="Attenuation">A reduction in signal strength commonly occurring while transmitting analog or
        digital signals over long distances.</term>
      <term full="Audio codec">PC subsystem capable of encoding and decoding a digital data stream of audio.</term>
      <term full="Audio Output Peripheral Device">Speakers, handset, and earphones.</term>
      <term full="Decibel Volt" abbr="dBV">A measurement of voltage ratio to 1 volt.</term>
      <term full="Digital Audio">Data stream that uses digital values to describe a sound wave in sampled intervals.</term>
      <term full="Extended Audio Frequency Range">The range from 1Hz to 60 kHz.</term>
      <term full="Headphones">Computer audio peripheral device with one or more small speakers.</term>
      <term full="USB Audio codec">Computer audio peripheral device with USB digital input/output, one or more
        analog audio outputs and one or more analog audio inputs.</term>
      <term full="Decibel" abbr="dB"/>
      <term full="Kilohertz" abbr="KHz"/>
      <term full="Millivolt" abbr="mV"/>
      <term full="Peripheral Sharing Device" abbr="PSD"/>
      <term full="Sony/Philips Digital Interface Format" abbr="S/PDIF"/>
    </tech-terms>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">
      A compliant Target of Evaluation (TOE) for this PP‐Module is any PSD that supports connectivity between
      one or more computers and one or more analog audio output peripheral devices. All of the requirements
      and restrictions that are defined in the PSD PP apply to a conformant TOE. A conformant TOE satisfies all
      of the specific data protection/isolation capabilities that are required by the PSD PP.
      <h:br/>
      <h:br/>
      A conformant TOE embodies one or more of the use cases defined in the PSD PP. It may also provide PSD
      functionality for additional types of computer interfaces (e.g., display, keyboard/mouse, user
      authentication device). In such a case, the TOE must claim conformance to all applicable PP‐Modules to
      the PSD PP.
      <h:br/>
      <h:br/>
      In general, computer audio may be routed in various ways:
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Analog audio signals</h:li>
        <h:li>Digital audio embedded in the video stream or independent digital audio (e.g., Sony/Philips Digital
          Interface Format, or S/PDIF)</h:li>
        <h:li>USB audio peripheral devices</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      Analog audio output requires special attention during TOE design as it may introduce analog leakage
      concerns. There is an additional concern an attacker may be able to use an audio output device
      as a low gain
      microphone for eavesdropping on the surrounding area or bridging an air‐gap to nearby computers.
      Analog audio output presents few security problems with respect to switching, since the person listening
      to the audio must be authorized to hear the output of all the connected computers. And in some
      operational environments, it is required that the user be able to hear more than one channel at a time.
      <h:br/>
      <h:br/>
      Digital audio embedded in a video stream or passed through separate lines is not a security concern for
      this PP‐Module since it does not introduce analog signal leakage vulnerabilities. The capability for digital
      video is addressed in the PP‐Module for Video/Display Devices.
      <h:br/>
      <h:br/>
      USB audio devices (i.e., codecs) are not authorized for use with the TOE. USB audio codecs have
      configuration memory that may be exploited to enable unauthorized data flows.
    </section>
    <section title="Test Environment for Evaluation Activities">
      In order to ensure that the TOE demonstrates the functionality required by the EAs, it is necessary for the
      evaluator to ensure that they have appropriate equipment to conduct the required testing. In addition to
      the equipment that is relevant for testing any PSD as defined in the PSD PP, the following additional
      equipment should be used in testing:
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Amplified speakers</h:b>
          – The tests depend upon the use of high‐quality system 2.1 standard
          and higher amplified speakers with a separate subwoofer.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Tone generator software application</h:b>
          – The tests require the use of a tone generator
          software application that can generate sine wave audio at configurable pitch (in Hz) and volume
          levels.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Computer microphone (analog)</h:b>
          – The tests require the use of an analog microphone to
          be connected to the TOE to demonstrate that it will not transmit audio signals when this occurs.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>3.5 mm stereo plug with open end wires or solderable tabs</h:b>
          – This plug is used by some of the tests
          in this Supporting Document to enable audio signal injection or detection at the TOE analog audio
          interfaces.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Digital voltmeter</h:b>
          – The tests require the use of a digital voltmeter to measure the DC
          voltage over TOE peripheral interfaces to confirm that current is not supplied to a connected
          microphone.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Audio signal generator</h:b>
          – The tests require the use of an audio signal generator that is
          capable of generating a sine wave with positive/negative bias from DC up to 100 KHz to test that
          the TOE does not experience audio signal leakage.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Audio spectrum analyzer software – The tests require the use of software with a Fast
          Fourier Transform (FFT) capability that can display real‐time audio spectrum data, including
          frequencies, attenuation dB, and voltage of audio signals, and is used to detect signal leakage
          between interfaces. Note that any use of a computer with audio spectrum analyzer software may
          be replaced by an audio spectrum analyzer or an Oscilloscope with FFT capability.</h:b>
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Oscilloscope</h:b>
          – The tests require the use of an oscilloscope to detect signal leakage
          between peripheral interfaces. Any oscilloscope with an FFT capability and bandwidth of at least
          1 MHz may be used. Note that any use of an oscilloscope may be replaced by a computer with
          audio spectrum analyzer software or an audio spectrum analyzer.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>Tone generator software</h:b>
          – The tests require the use of tone generator software to verify
          how data is routed.
        </h:li>
        <h:li>
          <h:b>USB dummy load</h:b>
          – The tests require the use of a USB dummy load
          to verify that electrical signals are not sent to non-selected computers.
        </h:li>
      </h:ul>
      This equipment is required in addition to that which is relevant for testing any PSD as defined in the PSD
      PP. Additional equipment may apply if the TOE claims support for additional peripheral types as defined
      by the other PP‐Modules that extend the PSD PP.
      <h:br/>
      <h:br/>
      When conducting testing, the evaluator must ensure that all combinations of switch selections are tested.
      For example, if testing a device with 2 audio output interfaces and eight computer interfaces, the
      evaluator may use two connected computers, but must change the connected ports several times to
      ensure that each of the possible permutations of switch positions is tested. Some equivalency arguments between ports are allowed.
    </section>
  </sec:Introduction>
  <sec:Conformance_Claims title="Conformance Claims" id="sec-cclaims" boilerplate="no">
    <CClaimsInfo cc-version="cc-2022r1" cc-approach="direct-rationale" display="yes">
      <cc-st-conf>exact</cc-st-conf>
      <cc-pt2-conf>extended</cc-pt2-conf>
      <cc-pt3-conf>conformant</cc-pt3-conf>
      <cc-pp-conf/>
      <cc-pp-config-with>
        <PP-cc-ref>Protection Profile for Peripheral Sharing Devices, Version 5.0</PP-cc-ref>
        <Mod-cc-ref>PP-Module for Keyboard/Mouse Devices, Version 2.0</Mod-cc-ref>
        <Mod-cc-ref>PP-Module for User Authentication Devices, Version 2.0</Mod-cc-ref>
        <Mod-cc-ref>PP-Module for Video/Display Devices, Version 2.0</Mod-cc-ref>
      </cc-pp-config-with>
      <cc-pkg-claim/>
    </CClaimsInfo>
  </sec:Conformance_Claims>
  <!-- 3.0 Security Problem Definition-->
  <sec:Security_Problem_Definition>
    This PP‐Module describes the security problem in terms of the threats the TOE is expected to address,
      assumptions about its operational environment, and any organizational security policies (OSPs) that the
      TOE is expected to enforce.
    <h:br/>
    <h:br/>
    Note that as a PP‐Module of the PSD PP, all threats, assumptions, and Organizational Security Policies (OSP)
      defined in the base PP will also apply to the TOE unless otherwise specified.
    <!-- 3.1 Threats -->
    <sec:Threats>
      <threats>
        <threat name="T.AUDIO_REVERSED">
          <description>A malicious agent could re-purpose an authorized audio output peripheral device by converting it to a          low‐gain microphone to eavesdrop on the surrounding audio or transfer data across an air‐gap          through audio signaling.</description>
          <!-- New mapping to build updated threat mapping table. -->
          <addressed-by>FDP_AFL_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by audio signal attenuation that prevents inadvertent transmission of audio data.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by ensuring
          the audio output jack cannot be used to transmit data into the TOE or a connected computer as a microphone.</rationale>
        </threat>
        <threat name="T.DATA_LEAK">
          <from base="bpp-psd"/>
          <description>This threat from the PSD PP also applies to the functionality defined in this PP-Module.</description>
          <!-- New mapping to build updated threat mapping table. -->
          <addressed-by>FDP_AFL_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by attenuating audio signals that could otherwise be data leakage.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by ensuring
          output data transit unidirectionally between interfaces.</rationale>
        </threat>
        <threat name="T.MICROPHONE_USE">
          <description>A malicious agent could use an unauthorized peripheral device such as a microphone, connected to          the TOE audio out peripheral device interface to eavesdrop or transfer data across an air‐gap through          audio signaling.</description>
          <!-- New mapping to build updated threat mapping table. -->
          <addressed-by>FDP_PDC_EXT.2/AO</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by only
          supporting audio output devices.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by ensuring
          output data transit unidirectionally between interfaces.</rationale>
        </threat>
        <threat name="T.SIGNAL_LEAK">
          <from base="bpp-psd"/>
          <description>This threat from the PSD PP also applies to the functionality defined in this PP-Module.</description>
          <!-- New mapping to build updated threat mapping table. -->
          <addressed-by>FDP_AFL_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by ensuring
          signals are filtered within the range of human hearing.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by ensuring
          signals transit unidirectionally between interfaces.</rationale>
        </threat>
        <threat name="T.UNAUTHORIZED_DEVICES">
          <from base="bpp-psd"/>
          <description>This threat from the PSD PP also applies to the functionality defined in this PP-Module.</description>
          <!-- New mapping to build updated threat mapping table. -->
          <addressed-by>FDP_PDC_EXT.2/AO</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by implementing audio functionality using an analog port so that digital audio devices or other unauthorized devices are not accepted.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_PUD_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates this threat by having the TOE's audio ports be unpowered so that devices that require a power source over this interface are not supported.</rationale>
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </sec:Threats>
    <!-- 3.2 Assumptions -->
    <sec:Assumptions>
      This PP‐Module defines the following additional assumption beyond those defined in the PSD PP
      <assumptions>
        <assumption name="A.NO_MICROPHONES">
          <description>Users are trained not to connect a microphone to the TOE audio output interface.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>The assumption is upheld by the objective since the users in the environment are trained
          not to connect a microphone to the TOE audio output interface.</consistency-rationale>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.NO_MICROPHONES">
            <rationale>The assumption is upheld by the objective
            since the users in the environment are trained
            not to connect a microphone to the TOE audio
            output interface.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </sec:Assumptions>
    <!-- 3.3 Organizational Security Policies -->
    <sec:Organizational_Security_Policies>
      <OSPs/>
    </sec:Organizational_Security_Policies>
  </sec:Security_Problem_Definition>
  <!-- 4.0 Security Objectives -->
  <sec:Security_Objectives>
    <!-- 4.1 Security Objectives for the TOE -->
    <!-- 4.2 Security Objctives for the Operational Environment -->
    <sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_Operational_Environment>
      <SOEs>
        <SOE name="OE.NO_MICROPHONES">
          <description>The operational environment is expected to ensure that microphones are not plugged into the TOE
            audio output interfaces.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>The Base-PP does not contain any requirements about microphone use, thus there is no
            conflict with the Base-PP.</consistency-rationale>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
    </sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_Operational_Environment>
    <!-- 4.3 Security Objectives Rationale -->
    <sec:Security_Objectives_Rationale/>
  </sec:Security_Objectives>
  <!-- 5.0 Security Requirements -->
  <sec:Security_Requirements title="Security Requirements">
    <!-- 5.1 PSD PP Security Functional Requirements Direction -->
    <base-pp id="bpp-psd" name="Peripheral Sharing Devices" product="Device" short="PSD" version="5.0">
      <git>
        <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/AO</url>
        <branch>main</branch>
      </git>
      <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/AO</url>
      <sec-func-req-dir>When a TOE claims compliance to this PP‐Module, it is necessary to make claims in the PSD PP
        requirements that are consistent with the functionality provided by the PP‐Module. The following sections
        describe any PSD PP claims that must be made when the TOE boundary includes the functionality
        described by this PP‐Module. Note that for some requirements, only certain individual elements within
        the SFR have been modified for this PP‐Module. Any SFR elements that were omitted from the selections
        below are to be included in a conformant ST unmodified from their definition in the PSD PP.</sec-func-req-dir>
      <!-- 5.1.1 Modified SFRs -->
      <modified-sfrs/>
      <!-- 5.1.2 Additional SFRs -->
      <additional-sfrs/>
      <con-toe>The PSD PP defines the boundaries of a PSD—a device that provides a mechanism for securely connecting
        a set of peripherals to one or more attached computers. This PP‐Module builds on this by defining
        functional capabilities that are specific to devices that can share audio output peripherals. The
        requirements of this PP do not prevent a conformant TOE from implementing mandatory requirements of
        the PSD PP.</con-toe>
      <con-sec-prob>The threats and assumptions defined by this PP-Module (see sections 3.1 and 3.2) supplement those defined
        in the PSD PP as follows:</con-sec-prob>
      <con-obj/>
      <con-op-en/>
      <con-mod ref="T.AUDIO_REVERSED">The PSD PP does not identify any threats specific to analog audio output peripheral devices. This threat is specific to analog audio output devices and therefore is an additional threat to this module supplementing those in PSD PP.</con-mod>
      <con-mod ref="T.DATA_LEAK">This threat is from the PSD PP, thus no conflict exists.</con-mod>
      <con-mod ref="T.MICROPHONE_USE">The PSD PP does not identify any threats specific to analog audio output peripheral devices. This threat is specific to analog audio output devices and therefore is an additional threat to this module supplementing those in PSD PP.</con-mod>
      <con-mod ref="T.SIGNAL_LEAK">This threat is from the PSD PP, thus no conflict exists.</con-mod>
      <con-mod ref="T.UNAUTHORIZED_DEVICES">This threat is from the PSD PP, thus no conflict exists.</con-mod>
    </base-pp>
    <!-- 5.2 TOE Security Functional Requirements -->
    <man-sfrs>
      <!-- 5.2.1 User Data Protection (FDP) -->
      <section title="User Data Protection (FDP)" id="fdp-mandatory">
        <ext-comp-def title="Audio Filtration" fam-id="FDP_AFL_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>Components in this family define the requirements for device filtering.</fam-behavior>
        </ext-comp-def>
        <ext-comp-def title="Peripheral Device Connection" fam-id="FDP_PDC_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family is defined in the PSD PP. This PP‐Module augments the extended family by adding one additional component, FDP_PDC_EXT.2. The new component and its impact on the extended family’s component leveling are shown below; reference the PSD PP for all other definitions for this family.</fam-behavior>
        </ext-comp-def>
        <ext-comp-def title="Powering Unauthorized Devices" fam-id="FDP_PUD_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>Components in this family define the requirements for unauthorized device powering.</fam-behavior>
        </ext-comp-def>
        <ext-comp-def title="Unidirectional Data Flow" fam-id="FDP_UDF_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>Components in this family define unidirectional transmission of user data.</fam-behavior>
        </ext-comp-def>
        <!-- FDP_AFL_EXT.1 Audio Filtration -->
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_afl_ext.1" id="fdp-afl-ext-1" name="Audio Filtration">
          <consistency-rationale>This SFR defines the filtering levels that outgoing audio signals must enforce.
            This function is specific to audio output devices and does not prevent the
            enforcement of any PSD PP SFRs.</consistency-rationale>
          <comp-lev>requires the TSF to enforce outgoing audio filtration levels.</comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
          <dependencies>FDP_PDC_EXT.1 Peripheral Device Connection</dependencies>
          <f-element id="fdp-afl-ext-1e1">
            <title>
              The TSF shall ensure outgoing audio signals are filtered as per the [<h:i>Audio Filtration
              Specifications Table</h:i>].
              <h:table name="Audio Filtration Specifications Table" border="1" style="width:100%">
                <h:tr class="header">
                  <h:td>Frequency (kHz)</h:td>
                  <h:td>Minimum Attenuation (dB)</h:td>
                  <h:td>Maximum Voltage After Attenuation</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>14</h:td>
                  <h:td>23.9</h:td>
                  <h:td>127.65 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>15</h:td>
                  <h:td>26.4</h:td>
                  <h:td>95.73 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>16</h:td>
                  <h:td>30.8</h:td>
                  <h:td>57.68 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>17</h:td>
                  <h:td>35.0</h:td>
                  <h:td>35.57 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>18</h:td>
                  <h:td>38.8</h:td>
                  <h:td>22.96 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>19</h:td>
                  <h:td>43.0</h:td>
                  <h:td>14.15 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>20</h:td>
                  <h:td>46.0</h:td>
                  <h:td>10.02 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>30</h:td>
                  <h:td>71.4</h:td>
                  <h:td>0.53 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>40</h:td>
                  <h:td>71.4</h:td>
                  <h:td>0.53 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>50</h:td>
                  <h:td>71.4</h:td>
                  <h:td>0.53 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:tr>
                  <h:td>60</h:td>
                  <h:td>71.4</h:td>
                  <h:td>0.53 mV</h:td>
                </h:tr>
              </h:table>
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall ensure outgoing audio signals are filtered as per
                <assignable>document reference to the table below.</assignable>
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            <note role="application">The above security requirement is designed to reduce the likelihood that speakers
              emitting a signaling event at frequencies outside the range of human hearing
              could be successfully used to bridge an air‐gap to another computer.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>The evaluator shall check the TSS to verify that the TOE audio function implementation properly filters
                the audio passing through the TOE.</TSS>
              <Guidance/>
              <Tests>
                <testlist>
                  <test>
                    <h:ol>
                      <h:li>Connect a computer to the TOE analog audio output peripheral interface and run audio analyzer
                    software on it.</h:li>
                      <h:li>For each connected computer, ensure it is selected, use its tone generator software to generate a
                    sine wave audio tone for each of the frequencies in the Audio Filtration Specifications table and verify in
                    the audio analyzer software that they are attenuated by at least the amount specified in the Audio
                    Filtration Specifications table.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Connect an oscilloscope to the TOE analog audio output peripheral interface and set it to measure
                    the peak‐to‐peak voltage.</h:li>
                      <h:li>
                        For each connected computer, perform Step 5 with the signal generator set to
                    the following settings:
                        <h:ul>
                          <h:li>Pure sine wave around the average voltage of half output (positive signal only), with the output
                        signal set to 2.00 V peak‐to‐peak, calibrating the signal with the oscilloscope as needed</h:li>
                          <h:li>Signal average to 0V (negative swing)</h:li>
                        </h:ul>
                      </h:li>
                      <h:li>Set the signal generator to generate the frequencies in Audio Filtration Specifications table and
                    verify the signal on the oscilloscope does not exceed the corresponding maximum voltage after
                    attenuation.</h:li>
                    </h:ol>
                  </test>
                </testlist>
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <!-- FDP_PDC_EXT.2 Peripheral Device Connection -->
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_pdc_ext.2" id="fdp-pdc-ext-2" name="Peripheral Device Connection" status="invisible">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <comp-lev>defines the types of physical devices that the TSF will permit to
            connect to it.</comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified</management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
          <dependencies>FDP_PDC_EXT.1 Peripheral Device Connection</dependencies>
          <f-element id="fdp-pdc-ext-2e1">
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices as defined in
              <assignable>devices specified in the PP or PP‐Module in which this SFR is defined</assignable>
              and
              <assignable>devices specified in another PP or PP‐Module that shares a PP-Configuration with the PP or PP‐Module in which this SFR is defined</assignable>
              upon TOE
              power up and upon connection of a peripheral device to a powered‐on TOE.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fdp-pdc-ext-2e2">
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices presenting authorized
                interface protocols as defined in
              <assignable>devices specified in the PP or PP-Module in which this SFR is defined</assignable>
              and
              <assignable>devices specified in another PP or PP‐Module that shares a PP‐Configuration with the PP or PP‐Module in which this SFR is defined</assignable>
              upon TOE power up and connection of a
                peripheral device to a powered‐on TOE.
            </title>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <!-- FDP_PDC_EXT.2/AO Peripheral Device Connection (Audio Output) -->
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_pdc_ext.2" id="fdp-pdc-ext-2-ao" name="Peripheral Device Connection (Audio Output)" iteration="AO">
          <consistency-rationale>This SFR defines the devices that are authorized by this PP‐Module. This is
            dependent on the other PP‐Modules that are claimed in the TOE’s ST. The
            Base‐PP is written specifically not to discuss the supported device types,
            instead leaving it to the various PP‐Modules to define what they support.</consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="fdp-pdc-ext-2e1-ai">
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices as defined in [<h:i>Appendix
                E</h:i>] and
              <selectables>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.1_AO_1">authorized devices and functions as defined in the PP‐Module for Keyboard/Mouse Devices</selectable>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.1_AO_2">authorized devices as defined in the PP‐Module for User Authentication Devices</selectable>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.1_AO_3">authorized devices as defined in the PP‐Module for Video/Display Devices</selectable>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.1_AO_4">no other device</selectable>
              </selectables>
              upon TOE power up and connection of a peripheral device
              to a powered‐on TOE.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fdp-pdc-ext-2e2-ai">
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow connections with authorized devices presenting authorized
              interface protocols as defined in [<h:i>Appendix E</h:i>] and
              <selectables>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.2_AO_1">authorized devices presenting authorized interface protocols as defined in the PP‐Module for Keyboard/Mouse Devices</selectable>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.2_AO_2">authorized devices presenting authorized interface protocols as defined in the PP‐Module for User Authentication Devices</selectable>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.2_AO_3">authorized devices presenting authorized interface protocols as defined in the PP‐Module for Video/Display Devices</selectable>
                <selectable id="fdp_pdc_ext.2.2_AO_4">no other devices</selectable>
              </selectables>
              upon TOE power up and connection of a peripheral device to a powered‐on TOE.
            </title>
            <note role="application">The TSF must claim conformance to a PP‐Configuration that includes each PP-Module
              contained in any selections. The ST author should select all devices and
              interfaces supported by the TOE.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>
              <Guidance>The evaluator shall verify that the operational guidance describes devices authorized for use with the TOE
                in accordance with the authorized peripheral device connections.</Guidance>
              <Tests>
                The evaluator shall verify that the TOE ports do not reject authorized devices and devices with authorized
                protocols as per the authorized peripheral device connections.
                <h:br/>
                <h:br/>
                Repeat this test for each of the following devices: analog headphone and analog
                speakers.
                <testlist>
                  <test>
                    <h:ol>
                      <h:li>Ensure the TOE is powered off.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Connect the authorized device to the TOE peripheral interface.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Power on the TOE. Verify the TOE user indication described in the operational user guidance is not
                    present.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Play an audio file on the connected computer and verify the sound is heard through the authorized
                    device.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Disconnect the authorized device, then reconnect it to the TOE peripheral interface.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Verify the TOE user indication described in the operational user guidance is not present.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Play an audio file on the connected computer and verify the sound is heard through the authorized
                    device.</h:li>
                    </h:ol>
                  </test>
                </testlist>
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <!-- FDP_PUD_EXT.1 Powering Unauthorized Devices -->
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_pud_ext.1" id="fdp-pud-ext-1" name="Powering Unauthorized Devices">
          <consistency-rationale>This SFR requires the TSF not provide power to any unauthorized device
            connected to the analog audio peripheral interface in addition to the PSD PP
            requirement of rejecting it. The PSD PP does not define any requirements to
            provide power to peripherals, therefore this does not conflict with the PSD PP
            but is supplementary to the PSD PP.</consistency-rationale>
          <comp-lev>the TSF to not power any unauthorized devices
            connected to the peripheral interface.</comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
          <dependencies>FDP_PDC_EXT.1 Peripheral Device Connection</dependencies>
          <f-element id="fdp_pud_ext-1e1">
            <title>The TSF shall not provide power to any unauthorized device connected to the
              analog audio peripheral interface.</title>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>
                The evaluator shall verify the TSS states that the TOE does not supply power to an unauthorized device
                connected to the analog audio output interface.
                <h:br/>
                <h:br/>
                The evaluator shall also verify that the TOE cannot be configured to supply power to a device connected
                to the analog audio output interface.
              </TSS>
              <Guidance>The evaluator shall verify that the guidance states that a microphone should never be connected to the
                TOE’s analog audio output interface.</Guidance>
              <Tests>
                <testlist>
                  <test>
                    <h:ol>
                      <h:li>Connect the amplified speakers directly to computer #1’s analog audio output interface (typically
                    green in color). Set the volume at the speakers to approximately 25 percent.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Connect the computer interface audio cable to the TOE audio output computer interface and
                    computer #1’s analog audio microphone input interface (typically pink in color) instead of the computer
                    analog audio output interface.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Connect an open 3.5 millimeter stereo plug to the TOE analog audio peripheral interface.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Power up the TOE and ensure computer #1 is selected.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Measure the DC voltage of stereo plug from the TOE analog audio peripheral interface between
                    the ground terminal and each one of the other two terminals (tip and ring) using a digital voltmeter.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Verify the voltage is 0.2 volts or less, ensuring there is no DC bias voltage supplied to the
                    microphone.</h:li>
                    </h:ol>
                  </test>
                </testlist>
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <!-- FDP_UDF_EXT.1 Unidirectional Data Flow -->
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_udf_ext.1" id="fdp-udf-ext-1" name="Unidirectional Data Flow" status="invisible">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <comp-lev>requires the TSF to provide unidirectional (one‐way)
            communications between a given pair of interface types.</comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
          <dependencies>FDP_APC_EXT.1 Active PSD Connections</dependencies>
          <f-element id="fdp_udf_ext-1-1">
            <title>
              The TSF shall ensure
              <assignable>type of data</assignable>
              data transits the TOE
                unidirectionally from the
              <assignable>origin point of data</assignable>
              interface to the
              <assignable>destination point of data</assignable>
              interface.
            </title>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <!-- FDP_UDF_EXT.1/AO Unidirectional Data Flow -->
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_udf_ext.1" id="fdp-udf-ext-1-ao" name="Unidirectional Data Flow" iteration="AO">
          <consistency-rationale>This SFR requires the specific types of peripheral data defined in this PP-Module
            to flow unidirectionally. This does not prevent the enforcement of
            any PSD PP SFRs.</consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="fdp-udf-ext-1e1-ai">
            <title>
              The TSF shall ensure that [<h:i>analog audio output data</h:i>] transits the TOE
              unidirectionally from the [<h:i>TOE analog audio output computer</h:i>] interface to the
              [<h:i>TOE analog audio input computer interface</h:i>].
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              For audio signals, the TOE analog audio output computer interface is
              considered to be unidirectional if it receives no signal greater than 45 dB of
              attenuation at the extended audio frequency range. It is very unlikely that this
              element can be satisfied unless all unselected computer interfaces are shorted
              to ground by the TSF.
              <h:br/>
              <h:br/>
              If the peripheral interface supports multiple signals (such as right and left
              audio, or audio bias), then all those supported signals should comply with the
              above SFR.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              The evaluator shall examine the Isolation Documentation to determine that it describes how the TOE
                enforces audio output data flow isolation from other TOE functions, such that the audio output peripheral
                interface is unidirectional and no data can be routed from a connected peripheral back to a connected
                computer. The description shall ensure the signal attenuation between any TOE audio output peripheral
                device interface and any other TOE computer audio output interface is at least 45 dB measured with a 2V
                input pure sine wave at the extended audio frequency range, including negative swing signal.
              <TSS/>
              <Guidance/>
              <Tests>
                Note: Data is considered not to transit the TOE if no signal greater than 45 dB of attenuation at the specific
                audio frequency is received.
                <h:br/>
                <h:br/>
                The evaluator shall perform the following test.
                <testlist>
                  <test>
                    <h:ol>
                      <h:li>Connect a computer to the TOE analog audio output peripheral interface, run its tone generator
                    software, and run audio analyzer software on the connected computer.</h:li>
                      <h:li>Perform steps 3‐6 for each TOE analog audio output peripheral interface.</h:li>
                      <h:li>For each connected computer, ensure it is selected, use the tone generator on the computer
                    connected to the TOE analog audio output peripheral interface to generate the designated frequencies,
                    and verify that the audio is not present on the selected computer’s audio analyzer software.</h:li>
                      <h:li>
                        Replace the selected computer with an oscilloscope and connect an external audio signal
                    generator to the TOE analog audio output peripheral interface. Perform step 5 with the signal generator
                    set to the following settings.
                        <h:ul>
                          <h:li>Pure sine wave around the average voltage of half output (positive signal only), with the
                      output signal set to 2.00 V peak‐to‐peak, calibrating the signal with the oscilloscope as
                      needed.</h:li>
                          <h:li>Signal average to 0v (negative swing)</h:li>
                        </h:ul>
                      </h:li>
                      <h:li>Set the signal generator to generate the designated frequencies, and verify the signal on the
                    oscilloscope is 11.2 mV or less.</h:li>
                    </h:ol>
                  </test>
                </testlist>
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </section>
    </man-sfrs>
    <opt-sfrs/>
    <sel-sfrs/>
    <obj-sfrs/>
    <impl-dep-sfrs/>
  </sec:Security_Requirements>
  <appendix title="Required Supplementary Information" id="req-supp-info">
    This Supporting Document refers in various places to the possibility that ‘supplementary information’ may
    need to be supplied as part of the deliverables for an evaluation. This term is intended to describe
    information that is not necessarily included in the Security Target or operational guidance, and that may
    not necessarily be public. Examples of such information could be a Letter of Volatility or isolation
    documentation. The requirement for any such supplementary information will be identified in the
    relevant PP, PP‐Module, or Supporting Document.
    <h:br/>
    <h:br/>
    The PSD PP requires an Isolation Document to be included with the TOE for evaluation of isolation
    requirements. The EAs the evaluator is to perform are captured under the appropriate SFR.
  </appendix>
  <bibliography>
    <entry id="base-pp">
      <tag>PP_PSD_V5.0 or PSD PP</tag>
      <description>Protection Profile for Peripheral Sharing Device, Version 5.0</description>
    </entry>
  </bibliography>
</Module>
